1337 w. Emperor Pl, Salt Lake City, UT 84123 (801) 699-3049 Erik.W.Huynh@gmail.com

#### **Profile:**

I'm a motivated student that received his Associate of Science degree through the Salt Lake Community College (SLCC) biotechnology program the fall of 2011. I am now currently working on my Bachelor's degree of Science through Utah Valley University with an graduation date of April 26th, 2013. Having been in the biotech program at SLCC, I have had many opportunities to work with current equipment and techniques as well as having interned at companies such as InnovaBio at SLCC and Pacific Northwest National Laboratory in Richland, WA. These opportunities have given me the experience necessary to work with project members towards a unified goal, in an organized and professional manner.

#### **Research Experience:**

## August 2012 - Present:

Employer: Biofire Dx

Job Title: Array assembly technician (Nanoplotter operator)

- One of five full-time operators of the Gesim Nanoplotter meant for printing oligos for Biofire Dx's patented FilmArray technology.
- Responsibilities include the operation and preventative maintenance of Nanoplotters.
   Contribute to the increase of quality, efficiency and production of FilmArray pouches through approved methods of Nanoplotter operations.
- Weekly meetings to discuss methods of increasing production and quality.

## May 2011 - August 2011:

Employer: Pacific Northwest National Laboratory

Job Title: Summer Intern

- Work with a team whose project focused on direct molecular evolution of Shiga toxin antibodies for an increase in affinity for use on ELISA antibody microarray.
- Cloning of target antibodies through PCR and yeast surface display. Using fluorescence-activated cell sorting to sort positive yeast clones.
- Printed and performed assays of Shiga toxin antibodies using a GeSim nano plotter and ELISA microarray.

### **September 2010 – May 2011**

Employer: InnovaBio

1337 w. Emperor Pl, Salt Lake City, UT 84123 (801) 699-3049 Erik.W.Huynh@gmail.com

Job Title: Student Intern

- Lead of a team whose project focused on the planning, coordinating and execution of highthrough put DNA cloning of *C. elegans* promoter regions.
- Designed the standard protocol for completing the goal to be later implemented in highthroughput.
- Collaboration with the client, peers and supervisors through team meetings and data presentations.
- Lab maintenance chores such as: Making solutions, ordering reagents, operating autoclave, cleaning glassware, making agar plates and LB broth.

1337 w. Emperor Pl, Salt Lake City, UT 84123 (801) 699-3049 Erik.W.Huynh@gmail.com

## Other Experience:

- Experience with various techniques such as: DNA/RNA preparation, PCR cloning, Real-time PCR sequencing, SDS-PAGE, and microarray.
- Second place in the 2011 annual Utah Valley University Biotechnology Poster Symposium.
   Awarded two semesters of UVU tuition.
- Three years of the Mathematics, Engineering, Science Achievement (MESA) program in high school, leading to knowledge on working with computers, math skills, as well as socialization with others.
- Two years of Future Business Leaders of America (FBLA). Gained skills in working well with others, working professionally, and gaining qualities of a leader.

## **Qualification / Education:**

Currently attended: Utah Valley University

Years attended: January 2012 to present

Major: Biotechnology

Graduation: April 26th, 2013 with a Bachelor's of Science from UVU.

Current GPA: 3.70

Currently attended: Salt Lake Community College

Years attended: January 2008 to present

Major: Biotechnology

Minor: Chemistry

Graduated: Fall 2011 with an Associates of Science degree

Current GPA: 3.5

Attended: Taylorsville High School

Years attended: 2007-2008

Cumulative GPA: 3.8

1337 w. Emperor Pl, Salt Lake City, UT 84123 (801) 699-3049 Erik.W.Huynh@gmail.com

## **References:**

Jean M. Bower, PhD Instructor of Biotechnology Salt Lake Community College 3491 W. Wights Fort Road West Jordan, UT 84088 Phone: 801-957-6337

Fax: 801-957-6335 jean.bower@slcc.edu

Mary L. Nelson Ph.D Assistant Director of InnovaBio Biotechnology Department Salt Lake Community College 3491 W. Wights Fort Rd West Jordan, UT 84088

Office: 801-957-6327 Fax: 801-957-6373 Mobile: 801-518-7565 mary.nelson@slcc.edu

Susan Varnum
Cellular and Biochemical Biology
Pacific Northwest National Laboratory
PO Box 999, Richland, WA 99354

Phone: 509-371-7299 susan.varnum@pnnl.gov

Yanfeng Zhang, Ph.D.
Biological Sciences Division
Pacific Northwest National Laboratory
790, Sixth Street,
MSIN J4-02
Richland, WA, 99352
Phone: 509-372-4790

Yanfeng.zhang@pnnl.gov

Meghan Hamilton

Technical Manufacturing Manager Biofire Dx 390 Wakara Way Salt Lake City, Utah 84108 Phone: 801-736-6354 x446 Meghan.Hamilton@BiofireDx.com

Joe Swarens
Manufacturing Coach
Biofire Dx
390 Wakara Way
Salt Lake City, Utah 84108
Phone: 801-736-6354 x869
Joe.Swarens@BiofireDx.com